# Chávez López Christopher César

# **Software Engineer**

Place of Residence: Dublin, Ireland
Contact Number: +353 0877409323
Email: doncesarts@gmail.com

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-c%C3%A9sar-ch%C3%A1vez-l%C3%B3pez-27566b12/

### **Professional Summary**

I am a software engineer with 12+ years of experience as full stack software engineer frontend (react/struts/spring mvc)/ backend (java/node), I have worked with companies from various industries mainly health-care, banks and retail, focused on the quality and efficiency of the software delivered to clients, leading projects using SCRUM as agile methodology.

Currently, I am interested on decentralized applications, based on React, Web3.js that interact with Solidity Smart Contracts running on Ethereum aside projects of this can be found on my github account https://doncesarts.github.io/

#### Technical skills

- Languages: Solidity, JavaScript, Java SE, J2EE, HTML,
- o Web: React, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, Web Design Systems, Truffle
- o Web 3 tools : Ganache, Truffle, Metamamask
- Databases: Oracle (9i, 10g), MySQL, MongoDB
- Servers: Apache Tomcat, WebLogic, WebSphere Application Server, JBoss
- o Frameworks: Struts, Struts2, JSF, RichFaces, Spring, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JPA
- o IBM Websphere: Application Server, DataPower, MQ, Message Broker

### Soft skills

Agile, self-taught, in constant research of new technologies, self-initiative, work under pressure, punctual, responsible, ability to analyze and design solutions. Taking part in annual IBM Hackathons.

# **Professional Experience**

# IBM Watson Health April 2016 - Today

# Software Engineer (Dublin, Ireland)

IBM Cúram Social Program Management (SPM)

Full-Stack development for IBM Cúram Universal Access:

- Using React, Redux, Web Design Systems for the front end.
- Exposing back-end capabilities through Rest APIs developed in Java.
- Design and development of the new IBM Intelligent Evidence Gathering responsive web client on React JS.
- Interacting with customers in order to help them to implement their solutions in a compliant way.

# Infosys November 2015 – April 2016

# Technology Analyst (Los Angeles, USA)

- Providing support to Southern California Edison on their Geographic Information Systems (GIS) based on Oracle Database Spatial (ODS).
- Working as a member of a multinational team, detecting issues and gathering all the necessary information for the offshore team.
- Implementing stored procedures consuming Oracle Database Spatial APIs in order to keep an accurate location of all assets.

# **GAPSI**

# August 2010 - October 2015

# Java EE / Middleware Consultant Sr (Mexico | Colombia)

Working through all stages of an IT solution: gathering clients' requirements, designing the overall architecture of IT solutions, creating technical specifications, developing proofs of concepts, planning the time and resources needed to implement a solution, implementing the core modules of the solutions, coordinating integration tests with different teams.

Technologies: Java EE, Java SE, IBM Integration Bus, IBM Message Broker, IBM MQ, IBM DataPower SOA Appliances, IBM Websphere Application Server.

### **SC Serasepro**

### **April 2009 - March 2010**

# Programmer Analyst - consultant (Mexico City)

Analysis, design and development of a J2EE application used as a workflow to plan validate and accept trade promotions for Pepsico Group, design of database tables, automation of initial load of data to the system.

Technologies: AJAX, Java script, Java Server Faces, Rich Faces, EJB, JPA, Oracle 9i, GlassFish.

### **UST IPN CICS**

### September 2008 - March 2009

**Programmer – Optometry (Mexico City)** UST IPN CICS is an investigation center for optometric treatments.

Analysis, design and implementation of the entire application, as well as interviews with experts to understand the rules, conditions and exceptions in order to give an accurate diagnosis in an optometric examination.

Technologies: J2EE, JSF, ICEfaces, JavaScript, JavaFX, JPA, Jasper Report, Mysql, Glass Fish.

### Inbursa Bank

# September 2007 - September 2008

Programmer Analyst - Integral Information System (Mexico City) Inbursa is one of the major banks in Mexico.

Development of modules of J2EE application, in the areas of debit cards, checks and electronic fund transfers, creation of reports, enhancement of security in different pages depending on the role of the user.

Technologies: Struts, Hibernate, Jasper Report, Jmeter, Files ACEGI Rules, Oracle, WebLogic.

#### **Education**

2017-2019	M.Sc. in Computing - Data Analytics at Dublin City University
2004-2008	Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering (UPIICSA IPN)

### Languages

Spanish: nativeEnglish: fluent

• French: intermediate (B1)

### **Certifications**

- IBM Certified SOA Associate
- Sun Certified Java Programmer (1.6)
- Oracle Certified Professional Java EE 5 Web Component Developer
- ITIL v3 Foundations Edition 2011
- Ethereum Blockchain Developer Bootcamp With Solidity (2021)
- Digital badges https://www.youracclaim.com/users/christopher-cesar-chavez-lopez/badges